Graham Vasquez

I'm a software engineer from **Philadelphia** (Go birds 🦅) with a love of building things that make people's lives *easier*. I've primarily worked in the web world, from crafting CSS to managing deployments in kubernetes.

agvasquez.dev **a**Github **a**Linkedin **b**graham@gvasquez.dev

Featured Projects

PHLask

PHLask is an application that aims to make finding free resources easier. We are almost finished with our v2 application that will allow for people to search for water, foraging, food, and clothing.

Talks and Events

PHL Code Club

I co-organize a monthly meetup in Philadelphia. Our focus is interactive sessions, but we also like to do project showcases or more traditional talks from time to time. It has been awesome to improve my communication and continue learning while building a community of like minded people.

Philly JS Club

- Typesafe API's powered by GraphQL
 - Explained the basics of the syntax, type system, execution, and some pros and cons of GraphQL.
 Emphasized the ease of use when paired with codegeneration.
- Gleam for Typescript Developers
 - Introduced the Gleam programming language as well as a short introduction to functional programming. Compared common patterns in Typescript with their Gleam counterparts.

Skills & Technologies

- Typescript
- Go
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- GraphQL
- Apache Kafka

Work Experience

iHeartMedia

Software Engineer - 1/2021 - Current

- Biggest Impact: Designed and built the prototype for an LLM powered article enhancer to increase site visits and ad revenue. I worked with our LLM provider to migrate their API to a webhook architecture to for more flexibility and to reduce timeouts at our ingress caching layer.
- Migrated the existing REST API that powers the subscriptions and content for several Premiere Network shows and is a recurring source of revenue to GraphQL. Now it better integrates with our existing infrastructure and internal tools, and stitches into our supergraph.
- Designed and maintained our code linting and formatting packages to reduce manual churn in PR reviews for all of our engineers.
- Took part in design discussions for migrating from NATS to SQS for messaging to reduce our costs for running NATS and reduce the maintenance burden for us to handle messaging between services.

Crowdcast

Software Engineer - 12/2020 - 1/2021

- Biggest Impact: Contributed to a key feature of Crowdcast V2 a staging area for presenters and guests to prepare before going live.
- This was just one of the improvements to scalability, reliability, and ease of use for our users I contributed as part of our upgrade to V2...
- Maintained legacy Angular, Firebase, MongoDB code and infrastructure.
- Contributed to architecture and technology decisions that are still shaping the future of the product - like simplifying handling real-time messaging subscriptions to improve stability and performance as the platform grows.

ClickPop

Web Developer - 09/2019 - 12/2020

- Built and maintained a number of production applications and sites using a variety of front and backend technologies.
- Build and manage SQL and NoSQL databases.
- Manage CI/CD scripts, focusing on Github Actions.

Education

Northampton Community College

Degree in Computer Science - 2014